The life of a dreamer, the days of a business and the nights in between.
Boogie Nights is a drama film directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
Set in 1977, back when sex was safe, pleasure was a business and business was booming,
idealistic porn producer Jack Horner aspires to elevate his craft to an art form.
Horner discovers Eddie Adams, a hot young talent working as a busboy in a nightclub, and welcomes him
into the extended family of movie-makers, misfits and hangers-on that are always around.
Adams' rise from nobody to a celebrity adult entertainer is meteoric, and soon
the whole world seems to know his porn alter ego, "Dirk Diggler".
Now, when disco and drugs are in vogue, fashion is in flux and the party never seems to stop,
Adams' dreams of turning sex into stardom are about to collide with cold, hard reality.
Eddie Adams / Dirk Diggler, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Jack Horner, played by Burt Reynolds.
Amber Waves, played by Julianne Moore.
Reed Rothchild, played by John C. Reilly.
Rollergirl, played by Heather Graham.
Buck Swope, played by Don Cheadle.
Boogie Nights is a 1997 American comedy-drama film written,
directed, and co-produced by Paul Thomas Anderson.
It is set in Los Angeles' San Fernando Valley and focuses on a young nightclub dishwasher who becomes a popular star of pornographic
films, chronicling his rise in the Golden Age of Porn of the 1970s through his fall during the excesses of the 1980s.
The film is an expansion of Anderson's mockumentary short film The Dirk Diggler Story (1988),
and stars Mark Wahlberg, Julianne Moore, Burt Reynolds, Don Cheadle, John C.
Reilly, William H.
Macy, Philip Seymour Hoffman, Nicole Ari Parker, and Heather Graham.
Boogie Nights premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 11, 1997, and was
theatrically released by New Line Cinema on October 10, 1997, garnering critical acclaim.
It was nominated for three Academy Awards, including Best Original Screenplay for Anderson,
Best Supporting Actress for Moore, and Best Supporting Actor for Reynolds.
The film's soundtrack also received acclaim.
It has since been considered one of Anderson's best works, one of the greatest
films of the 1990s, and one of the best films of all time by Variety.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, adultery,
pornography, robbery, husband wife relationship.
The tone is emotional.